(カブト)それは 蒲の穂だよ。
(幽鬼丸)え？
(カブト)穂先を つまんでごらん。
わっ！
へぇ～。
フン…。
ここが 例の湖だ。
Those are cattails.
Huh?
Grab the tips.
This is the lake.
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
explain to me this happiness
anata ga saikin taiken shita
that you just got to experience?
shiawase wa ittai nan desu ka
or maybe you're so blessed
megumare sugite ite
that you can't even remember it
omoidasenai kamo
that you stand here now
ima koko ni iru koto
that you still live and breathe
iki wo shite iru koto
I realised that they all were miracles
tada soredake no koto ga
just by themselves
kiseki da to kidzuku
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
you know the closer you get to something
the tougher it is to see it
and i'll never take it for granted
it's fine to say you'll never give up
oi tsudzukete kita yume
and to keep chasing your dreams
akiramezu ni susumeyo nante
but the more time you spend talking big
kirei goto wo ieru hodo
the less you get done
nanimo dekicha inai kedo
I will press that handful of courage against my heart
hito nigiri no yuuki wo mune ni
and with its help survive another day
ashita wo ikinuku tame ni
and i'll never take it for granted
let's go
Encounter
ホントだ。 湖の水って
しょっぱくないんだ。
It’s true, lake water
isn’t salty at all.
海とは違うんだ。
It’s different from the ocean.
でも ボク
海だって知らないけどね。
Although... I’ve never seen
the ocean either.
今…！
ん？
Just now...
Hmm?
フフフ。
さて このあたりでいいかな。
Well, around here should do...
フフッ。
フフフ！
何が おかしいんだい？
What’s so funny?
フフッ 何か おもしろいことが
始まる気がして。
I have a feeling something fun
is about to start.
あぁ おもしろいことをするんだ。
Yeah, we’re going to
have some fun.
これを つけてもらえるかな？
Can you put this on?
これは キミの能力を引き出す…。
This is a special medicine,
which will draw out your power...
いや おもしろいことが起きる
特別な薬だよ。
no, make something
interesting happen.
うっ！ うぅ…。
うぅ… うぁ～！
《来る…》
It’s coming...
あ… うぅ…。
《限界か…》
That’s the limit.
《確かにいる この湖に。
It’s there... no doubt about it.
In this lake...
そして この子は…
この子は使えますよ➡
And... this child...
we can use him.
大蛇丸様》
Orochimaru-sama...
(パックン)なんじゃ？ カカシ。
What is it, Kakashi?
(カカシ)これを里に。
Take this to the village.
五代目に届け
分析するよう頼んでくれ。
Have the Fifth Hokage analyze it.
ん!? 何じゃこれは。
What is this...?
(カカシ)大蛇丸の仲間と思われる
敵の術にやられた➡
One of Shino’s parasitic insects
which fell victim to a Jutsu...
It was an enemy believed to be
a follower of Orochimaru.
シノの寄壊蟲だ。
大蛇丸じゃと？
Orochimaru?!
(カカシ)足跡からすると
他にも敵が５～６人➡
According to the footprints,
there are five or six more
that we must pursue.
オレたちは コイツらを
追跡しなければならない。
(カカシ)大至急で頼むよ。
Move quickly.
任せろ。
(カカシ)頼んだよ。
Leave it to me!
I’m counting on you.
(カカシ)よし オレたちは 敵を追う。
All right, we’re going to
pursue the enemy.
この方角の延長線上を
範囲を広げて捜すよ。
Increase the range...
spread out and search.
わずかな痕跡も見逃すな。
Don’t miss a single trace of them!
(ヒナタ)はい。
(赤丸)ワン！
(キバ)おう！
Right!
Yeah.
(リンジ)あなたの留守は このリンジが➡
I, Rinji, will take care of things in
your absence, so don’t worry.
しっかり 仕切っておきますよ
ご心配なく。
(紅蓮)任せたよ。
I’m counting on you.
(キギリ)フンッ 結局は オレたちを➡
I guess she still
can’t trust us.
信用できないだけじゃないすか。
(キギリ)大蛇丸のアジトを
知られたくないから➡
She doesn’t want us to learn
about Orochimaru’s hideout,
オレたちを こんなところに
押し込めて。
so we’re shoved into
a place like this...
(リンジ)あの人は それだけ
慎重な方なんだよ。
She’s extremely cautious.
だからこそ
仕えて間違いは起きねえ。
It’s why she rarely
makes mistakes.
逆に 信用できるってもんだ。
So conversely, we can trust her.
(キギリ)殺された連中は
大蛇丸に会うのがイヤで➡
The ones who were killed
were trying to run away
because they didn’t want
to see Orochimaru.
逃げようとしたんですぜ。
ホントに 信用できるんすか？
Can you really trust her?
(ガマ力)ワンツー ワンツー！
One, two... One, two...
(ナルト)ワンツー ワンツー。
(自来也)フフン！ やっとるな ナルト。
You’re working hard, Naruto.
ガマ力さんの厳しさが
お前を鋼のように鍛え➡
Gamariki-san’s sternness will temper you
like steel and nurture you...
成長させ やがては…。
≪(女たち)キャ～ 気持いい スゴイ！
– Awesome!
– An outdoor bath!
やがては 強靭な肉体を作り上げ➡
And before long, your body
will be tough enough...
この世のあらゆる誘惑を
はねつけ… ムフフフ！
to repel any temptation
of the world--!
あらゆる誘惑を
はねつけられない～！
Can’t repel...
any temptation of the world...
(ガマ力)もう！ どうしてこんな
簡単なこともできないのよ！
Goodness! Can you even do
something this simple?!
そんなの知るか！
ガマ力さんの教え方が➡
What’re you saying?!
It’s the way you teach that’s bad!
わりいんじゃねえのか!?
あら 逆ギレ？
自分のヘタレを棚に上げ？
Oh? You’re blaming me?
You think you’re better than me?
フン！ もうヤダ！
ガマンできねってばよ！
Humph! Forget it!
I can’t take this anymore!
コラッ！ お待ちなさい！
愛のムチ！
Hey! Stop right there!
Love Smack!
うわっ！
クソ～ッ！ いきなり後ろから
卑怯じゃねえかよ！
Damn it!
Coming at me from behind...
That’s cowardly!
あらっ 痛い！
もうムリだ！ もうムリだ！
– Take this! And that!
– Stop!
やめなさい。 やめなさいって！
(２人)うわぁ～！
(女の子)キャ～ッ！
(女の子)なに？
(女の子)なにこれ？
What is this?!
(女の子)お湯がなくなっちゃった。
The water’s all gone.
(女の子)行きましょう。
Let’s go.
のぉ～！
No!
なにが修業だってばよ！
You call this training?!
Slobbering around like that--?!
ベロベロなめまわしやがって！
これは愛のムチ！
This is the Love Smack!
なにが愛のムチだ。 もうコンビ解消だ！
Forget your Love Smack!
This duo is disbanded!
こっちこそ ごめんだわ！
Fine with me!
いい加減にせんか ２人とも！
That’s enough! Both of you!
(２人)へっ？
(自来也)ったくのぉ。
As if Naruto isn’t enough...
But you too, Gamariki-san...
ナルトだけなら まだしも
ガマ力さんが ついていながら…。
いえねぇ ジラちゃんの言いたい
ことは とてもわかるのよ。
Well, you know Jira-chan,
it’s not like I don’t understand.
わかるんだけど…。
I do, but...
風遁と水遁のコラボ忍術には
ガマとのコンビネーションが最も重要だ。
For a Collaboration Ninjutsu using
the Wind Style and Water Style,
nothing is more important
than synchronizing with the toad.
(ガマ力)だからこそ なおさら
体の相性で決めないと 私… ムリ。
All the more reason why...
our bodies must be compatible,
or it’s useless for me.
ああ！ 相性が合わねえんだから➡
Yeah well, we aren’t compatible,
他に相性がよさそうなヤツを
捜したほうが 断然早えってばよ。
so it’ll be faster if
we find someone who is.
フン！
それは一理あるかもしれんのぉ。
Hmm... That may be a good idea.
だからといって お前 その手じゃ
口寄せなどできんじゃろ。
However... you can’t summon
with that arm, can you?
ヘッ オレの回復の速さを
忘れたわけじゃねえよな エロ仙人。
Hah! You haven’t forgotten
how fast I recover, have you?
Pervy Sage!
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
えっ！？ ああ～っ！
H-Huh?!
(ガマ吉)久しぶりじゃのぉ。
Long time no see...
(ガマ竜)ナルト君 こんにちはです。
Hello, Naruto-kun!
あれ？ ガマ吉と竜…。 ああっ!?
Huh?! Gamakichi and Tatsu...?
ほぉ～ でかくなったのぉ。
Oh, you’ve grown!
ハハッ お前たちも知らない間に
大きくなったんだなぁ。
You guys’ve gotten pretty big.
当たり前じゃあ。
Of course we have!
いっぱい いっぱい
おやつ食べたからです。
It’s because of all the snacks
we’ve eaten.
それより なんのために
呼び出したんなら？
Anyway, why’d you summon us?
おう そうだった。
Oh yeah, I have some
important business!
オレとお前たちとで
体の相性を磨くんだ！
I want to refine our compatibility.
あん!?
それって おいしいの？
What?!
Does that taste good?
《大蛇丸様》
Orochimaru-sama!
《アイツは…》
That’s...
((ハァ ハァ…。
ハァ ハァ…。
遅かったね。
You’re late.
大蛇丸様は 幻幽丸を選んだ。
Orochimaru-sama has
chosen Genyumaru.
そして今のが うちは サスケ…➡
And that was Sasuke Uchiha
just now...
大蛇丸様の次の器…。
Orochimaru-sama’s next vessel...
(大蛇丸)サスケ君
これまでの修業の成果…➡
Sasuke-kun, let me see the results
of your training thus far.
見せてもらうわよ。
(サスケ)お前が相手をするのか？
You’re my opponent?
まさか…。
By no means.
しびれるわね…。
How impressive.
千人を前に
顔色一つ変えない その表情。
A thousand foes stand before you
and you don’t even bat an eyelid.
≪あの男… どれほどの器か…≫
That man... how strong is he...?
(大蛇丸)始めなさい。
Begin.
(忍者たち)うお～！
ぐわ～！
ぐっ！
うわっ！
サスケ君… やはり あなたは…。
Sasuke-kun... You are truly...
何なの… アイツは…➡
What the--!
That guy’s... overwhelming...
あの圧倒的な…。
じゃあよ そういうことなら
ビシビシ鍛えちゃるけんの。
Well, if that’s the case,
we’ll train you really hard.
あぁ 頼むぜ！
フッ…。
Yeah, you do that!
よっしゃ！ ミュージックスタート！
All right! Start the music!
♪♪「かえるのうたが」
I can hear... the frog song.
♪♪「きこえてくるよ」
♪♪「かえるのうたが」
I can hear... the frog song.
あっ？ エッ？
これは何が始まったんだ？
Huh?! Huh?! What’s going on here?
♪♪「あれ!?
うまそなハエが飛んでいる～」
I see a yummy-looking fly.
♪♪(ガマ吉/ガマ竜)「ブンブンブンブン ブーン ブーン」
いただきま～。
Here I go!
何しちょる ナルト。
Come on, Naruto.
ガマ竜と心を通わせるんじゃ
ついてこい！
Keep up with Gamatatsu,
connect with his soul.
何だよ！ これのどこが
修業なんだってばよ！
Cripes! Just what part of
this is supposed to be training?!
フー… わかっとらんのぉ ナルトは…。
You just don’t get it,
do you, Naruto...?
これで全部か？
Is that it?
全員にとどめは さしてないわね。
You didn’t kill all of them...
How naïve.
まだまだ甘い。
殺したいヤツは他にいる。
There are others I’d rather kill.
非情にならなければ
イタチには勝てないわよ。
Unless you become heartless,
you will not defeat Itachi.
アイツの前では非情になるさ。
When I stand before him,
I’ll be heartless,
whether I want to be or not.
否が応でもな…。
≪返り血を１滴も…。
Not even a tiny spurt of blood...
この子を見てると…➡
When I watch this boy...
天才と呼ばれていた自分が
惨めに思えてくるわね…≫
I look back to the time
I was called a genius...
and think how ridiculous that was.
≪あと少し…➡
Very soon... so very soon,
he will be mine...!
ほんの少しで私のもの…≫
(大蛇丸)久しぶりね。
It’s been a long time, Guren.
紅蓮 よく来たわ。
I’m glad you came.
(大蛇丸)そうよ 彼が次の私の器。
Yes, he is my next vessel...
あなた
まだ あきらめていないのね。
You haven’t given up yet,
have you...
私の器になること。
on being my vessel?
あなたの能力… 魅力的よね。
Your abilities... are quite appealing.
初めて会ったときは驚いたわ。
When I first met you,
I was very shocked.
大蛇丸様…。
Orochimaru-sama...
《違う…》
You’re wrong...
((あなたの力 興味があるわ。
The power you have...
I’m interested.
(一緒に いらっしゃい))
Come with me.
≪紅蓮 : あのとき
その力に魅入られたのは➡
Back then...
I was the one who was enchanted
by your power...
私のほうだ。
Your strength...
大蛇丸様の力 そのものになりたい
と私は願った≫
To become like you... was my wish.
あなたを呼んだのは他でもない。
There’s only one reason
why you were summoned...
私のために
働いてもらえるかしら？
I need you to do something for me.
もちろんです。 私は そのために➡
Of course. That is the reason
why I serve you, Orochimaru-sama..
大蛇丸様に
お仕えしているのですから。
この仕事はね どうしても
あなたに やってもらいたいのよ。
I really want you
for this mission.
いいえ
あなたにしかできない仕事よ。
In fact... you’re the only one
who can do it.
私にしか？
Only me?
(大蛇丸)そうしたら
もう一度 考えてみてもいいわよ。
Then perhaps,
I may want to reconsider.
私の器に
いちばん ふさわしいのは誰か…。
Who... is the best suited to
become my vessel.
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…。
《かなり疲労が激しい。
He’s quite fatigued...
Perhaps we should rest a bit.
少し休んでいくか》
(女たち)キャハハハ！
あ～あ…。
クソッ… あんな メチャクチャな動きに
どうやって合わせりゃいいんだよ。
Dammit! How am I supposed to
keep up with that ridiculous movement?!
やっぱ
ガマたちと心を通い合わせんのは➡
I guess trying to connect
heart-to-heart is crazy...
ムチャがあんのかな…。
especially with the toads.
Can you... connect hearts?
(幽鬼丸)心って通い合うの？
だ… 誰だってばよ！
Wh-Who the hell are you?!
お前 どこから…。
Where’d you come from...?
(幽鬼丸)
心が通うって どういうこと？
What does it mean to
connect heart-to-heart?
え!? そりゃあ➡
Huh?! W-Well...
こっちの気持が相手に伝わって
相手の気持が こっちにも…。
My feelings are understood
by someone else...
and that person’s feelings
reach me as well.
そんなことって あるんだね。
そりゃ あるぞ。
Then it happens?
Y-Yeah, well sure.
いや… 一生懸命 思ってれば
いつか いつか 伝わるんだ。
I mean, if you really focus
on it hard...
Then one day...
one day, it’s sure to connect.
そしたら サスケだって…。
And even Sasuke...
思ってるヤツが いるところが
帰ってくる場所なんだ！
Then that person you’re thinking
about will know where home is.
まぁ… 何 言ってんのか
わかんねえよな。
Oh... You wouldn’t know
what I mean, would you...
いきなり こんな話されてもよ。
if I start rambling on like that?
じゃあ 誰かが
ボクのことを思ってくれたら➡
So if someone is thinking
about me,
そこが
ボクの帰る場所になるんだね。
then that’s the place I go back to?
あぁ！ そこが お前の帰る場所だ。
Yeah... that’s home.
フフフフ… いいこと聞いた。
I learned something good.
そうだろ そうだろ。
Yeah, right?
フフフフ… フフフフ…。
あ… そういえば お前 名前は…？
By the way, what’s your name–
Huh? Hey?
あれ!? …ん？
アイツ どこ消えたんだ？
That kid... where’d he disappear to?
カカシ先生 こんな所で
のんびりしてて大丈夫なのかよ。
Kakashi-sensei! Is it okay to be
relaxing in a place like this?
(シノ)捜索は オレの蟲たちに任せ
今は 体を休めておくことだ。
Leave the search to my parasitic insects
and rest your bodies.
そうだよ キバ君。
He’s right, Kiba-kun.
Yeah... We haven’t found the enemy yet.
(カカシ)あぁ。
敵の正体も つかめていない今➡
闇雲に動くのは危険だ。
It’s dangerous to act recklessly.
それに あの結晶の術…➡
Besides, that Crystal Jutsu...
パックンが戻るまでは
慎重に動いたほうがいい。
Until Pakkun returns,
we must act with caution.
(綱手)入れ！
Enter!
(シズネ)綱手様…
カカシさんより 伝令です。
Tsunade-sama...
Kakashi-san sent a messenger.
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
パックンじゃないか。
Well well, it’s Pakkun.
ハァ ハァ… カカシからの伝言の前に
まずは 水くれ。
Before I give you Kakashi’s message,
give me a drink of water.
あ～ いい湯じゃ！
Ahh... What a nice bath.
あれ!? ガマ吉
その体 どうしたんだってばよ？
Huh?! Gamakichi?!
What’s with that body?
何 言っとるんじゃ！
What’re you saying?
I’d be in everyone’s way at the baths
with such a huge body.
あんな大きな体じゃ
公衆浴場では迷惑じゃけん➡
So I used Ninjutsu to
make myself smaller.
忍術で小さくなっとるんじゃ。
ふ～ん…
おもしろい術 使えるんだなぁ。
Hey, that’s an interesting Jutsu
you have.
にいちゃん
やっぱ 温泉は いいね～。
Brother, hot springs are so nice.
修業の疲れが ぶっ飛ぶよ。
Washes away all the fatigue
of training.
何が修業だ！ お前は ハエを
追っかけてただけじゃねえか！
What training?!
You were chasing flies all day.
な～に言っとるんじゃ！ あれが
ワシらの コンビ修業の基本じゃわい。
What’re you saying?
That’s the foundation of
our collaboration training.
修業って あんな メチャクチャなフリ
真似できるわけねえだろうが。
Training? Who could copy
that wacky stuff?
誰が 真似せえと言った？
この修業はなぁ➡
Who said anything about copying?
This training is about feeling
what’s in Gamatatsu’s heart
ガマ竜の心を読み
それに合わせる修業よ。
and responding to it.
えっ？ ガマ竜の…？
Huh? Gamatatsu...?
あ～ いい湯だねぇ。
This bath feels so good...
(ガマ吉)タイミングや
合わせることなど どうでもいい。
Never mind about the timing
or matching his movements.
Feeling what’s in his heart
and responding to it,
いかに相手の心を読み それに
応えてやれるかが コンビの神髄じゃ。
that’s the essence of collaboration.
そうやって初めて
心が通い合うってもんじゃ。
At that point, for the first time,
you’ll be in synch.
相手の心… 気持…。
Your partner’s heart... feeling it.
そうか… そうだよな。
I see...
Yeah, I get it.
もう一度… もう一度
やらせてくれってばよ！
Let me, let me try it once more!
今度こそ コラボ忍術の修業
ものにしてみせる！
Combination Jutsu training!
This time, I’ll show you I can do it!
わ～い！ 修業 修業！
Yay! Training, training!
Huh?!
What happened?!
The water’s all gone again!
Hey Gamatatsu, shape up!
I have a bellyache.
The sexy voices of lots of women...
Oh, they all left just now.
Nooooooooo!
Oh my god! Oh my god!
oh my god oh my god
yesterday's mistake got me discouraged, but
kinou no shippai de kojiketatte
Thank you! Thank you!
gottsuanda gottsuanda
my new clothes got splashed with some sauce, wow
onyuu no fuku ni sousu ga hanete wao
don't mind, don't mind, if I stay feeling like this I'll have a tear in my eyes
donmai donmai shizunda mama ja namida mo my eyes
I may be hungry and angry
donna ni hangurii de angurii demo
but I'll grab a bowl to eat and start dancing!
donburi kutte danshingu
We'll always be pals my brother!
orera itsumo demo nakama daro burazaa
hit me with an upwind or strong wind or a storm I'm ready so come on!
tatoe gyarufuu kyoufuu arashi ga fuitemo bacchikoi kamon
we may be apart but we'll still be under the same sky
hanaretetemo onaji sora no shita de
so smile and hang on
saa waratte funbatte
lets do it do it do it do it
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
even if morning doesn't come, yay yay
tatoe asa ga konakutatte yay yay
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
we'll still watch the dream together, yay yay
kimi to tomo ni yume wo miru ze yay yay
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
no matter what, don't ever, ever give up, yay yay
nani ga nandemo aa demo kou demo akirameru na yay yay
Bring it, bring it baby!
bacchikoi bacchikoi baby
morning will always come after night, yay yay
donna yoru mo asa wa kuru ze yay yay
nanananana
Next Episode
Naruto! You’ve got a long way to go
えっ!?
えいっ！ イタッ！
if you’re getting distracted
by what you can see.
≪(女の子)キャーッ！
また お湯が なくなったじゃない。
– I’m hungry...
– I know already!
Hey! Found a grasshopper!
こら ガマ竜 しっかりせぇ！
(ガマ竜)お腹 痛い…。
Then open yourself up a bit more
and concentrate on
Gamatatsu’s moves, will ya?!
のぉ～！
たくさんの女子の黄色い声！
– Munch time!
– That's what I'm doing!
Hey, there’s a big caterpillar...
You need to concentrate more
to feel the emotional vibe from Gamatatsu,
今 全員 上がってったってばよ。
and express it through
your own style.
のぉ～っ!!
Will you shut up for a second?!
I think I’m about to
get something here!
Connecting Hearts
Next Time: “Connecting Hearts”